# Margo Roi

## **Senior Web Engineer**

Email: margo@finua.org

Phone: +358456699199

margoroi.works

#### **PROFILE**

#### Areas of expertise and interest:

- Front-End: TypeScript, React.js, project bundlers (Webpack, Parcel, Fusebox), Redux, React Native,
  ClojureScript, Progressive Web Apps, Service Workers, functional JavaScript (RxJS, RamdaJS), CSSinJS
  (styled components, emotion etc.), CSS processors (sass, less, postcss etc.), CSS resets, Accessibility, User
  Experience, vertical decomposition (micro front-ends), WebGL
- Back-End: Node.js, PostgreSQL, Next.JS, GraphQL, Clojure, nginx, microservices, web sockets API, API Design, SSR, MongoDB.
- Cloud & DevOps: AWS (Lambda, S3, Route 53, Amplify, etc.), Google Cloud Platform, Docker, Netlify, Digital Ocean, Vercel
- Design: Service Design, Digital Art Direction, Figma (Web Design), Sketch, Design Systems, Design Tokens, Branding.
- Thought Leadership: public speaking, teaching experience, organizing workshops and tech-related events, writing tutorials and technical articles, leading a developer team.

I am a Senior Software Engineer, tackling technical challenges at different stages of the project: from service design to deployment and refactoring, taking roles of an architect or a creative lead in teams. I would describe myself as business-oriented, technology-agnostic, with high-level concept knowledge, and a broad overview of the current digital trends.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

May 2024 - September 2024

Senior Software Engineer at Reaktor, Helsinki

This was a role I took on as a challenge: despite being an engineer, I was made a project coordinator on an aviation project. My responsibilities included communication with the client and the team, technical planning, and documentation working is a 3 timezone environment.

February 2022 - present

Founder of FinUA, Helsinki

Founded a non-profit helping Ukrainians get the necessary information when coming to Finland. Tech lead of the project: established partnerships, created volunteer teams, formulated strategic vision for the non-profit.

## December 2021 – December 2023

#### Senior Web Engineer at Motley, Helsinki

Mentored developers inside the team. Designed and implemented an API layer that enabled data integration with external systems. Worked on client and impact-driven project to accomplish company's missions to be socially responsible.

Used my expertise in Web Development to create full-stack applications for my clients: from DigitalOcean droplets with NodeJS and PostgreSQL to NextJS-powered front-end applications with Tailwind.

Team player: worked among designers and project managers to create, estimate and manage projects.

## December 2019 – November 2021

#### Senior Software Engineer at Nitor Creations, Helsinki

Clojure and Clojure Script Developer. The latest project has been an open-source white label project for CSC called REMS.

## August 2017 – November 2019

#### Senior Software Engineer at Futurice, Helsinki

Consultant Software Developer with a diverse skills spectrum:

AWS (Lambda, S3, Route 53, etc.), Docker, Google Cloud, Node.js, GraphQL, React.js, Redux, TypeScript, styled-components, project architecture and setup, building environments and systems for the clients that include design systems, front-end, back-end, devops. I am a person that can lead a technical team with the expertise as well as communicate efficiently with the client and be business oriented, while having a great collaboration with designers.

#### February 2017 - June 2017

#### Front-End Developer at Holvi, Helsinki

Worked on the UI layer closest to the user. Worked on updating application architecture, design system of the core web application, UI element frameworks, implementation of web app layouts and interactions, micro interactions, visual polish. Implemented improvement and additions to product visual library. Used technologies such as AngulaJS, SASS, CoffeeScript, Gulp, Grunt, Bootstrap, Django Framework, Python, Visual Regression Testing.

### April 2016 – January 2017

### JavaScript Engineer at Frosmo, Helsinki

Developer on a very low level of JavaScript knowledge. Mastered Chrome Debugger and Vanilla JavaScript, DOM API, BOM API. Curated company-sponsored workshop for GirlsInTech.

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

## September 2020 - March 2022

#### Online course teachers and author, Otus

Lecturer in an online course: designed and conducted multiple classes for Node.JS developers as a part of online school Otus, including such topics as: profiling, clustering, optimisation, ReactJS, Redux pattern, functional programming.

## September 2017-December 2017

#### Haaga-Helia UAS, guest lecturer

Designed and taught Web Development 101 course.

### **EDUCATION**

Jan 2014 - Jun 2019

## Haaga-Helia UAS, Business Information Technology

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science and Business Consulting. Studied both technical and business sides of the IT industry. Specialized in Web Development.

Team player: worked among designers and project managers to create, estimate and manage projects.

#### **Thesis**

As a huge fan of Fashion Tech, I wrote my thesis on outfit suggestions based on weather conditions. I love to experiment with data and find unusual ways to utilize it. The most recent contribution was a library apparent temperature that I released to npm.